嘿 Leonard...
Leonard...
我有个坏消息
I've got terrible news.
怎么回事?
What's going on?
在我告诉你之前
Before I tell you,
我觉得应该先铺垫一下
perhaps I should soften the blow.
你的脸左右很对称
You're face is pleasingly symmetrical.
就直接说吧
Just tell me.
一队瑞典物理学家
A Swedish team of physicists
准备抢在我们之前做超流体涡旋实验
is trying to scoop our super-fluid vortex experiment.
啊 这有点糟啊
Oh, well, that kind of stinks.
"这有点糟啊"?
"That kind of stinks"?
你为什么没有很失望?
Why aren't you more upset?
是我铺垫得太多了吗?
Did I soften the blow too much?
因为你看起来更像毕加索的抽象画
Because this here is more like a Picasso painting.
我们要怎么办?
What are we going to do?
马上开始实验
Perform the experiment immediately.
我也想啊 但我们需要液氦
I'd love to, but we need liquid helium
我们的订单已经延期交货一个月了
and our shipment's on back order for a month.
一个月? 你逗我呢?
A month? What? Are you kidding me?
这么长时间足够你铺垫了啊
That would have been a good time for you to soften the blow.
你的T恤很衬你的蓝眼睛
That shirt brings out the blue in your eyes.
谢谢 你嘴真甜
Thank you. Aren't you sweet.
我们去看看大学里还有没有
Let's go check to see if the university
液氦存货了
has any helium in reserve.
你知道我今天差点就没穿这件T恤吗?
Did you know that I almost didn't wear this shirt today?
嘿 Barry 我们碰上麻烦了
Hey, Barry, we're in trouble.
我们需要液氦... 系里面还有库存吗?
We need liquid helium... Does the department have any we can use?
不好意思 液氦不是很充足
Sorry, there's a shortage.
剩下的那些 我要拿来做量子激发研究
And what we do have I need for my quantum excitation study.
但你用不了那么多啊
But you won't need much for that.
对 但如果成功了
True, but if it's successful,
我要拿它给气球充气开派对
I'm having a party with balloons.
别这样 Barry 有一个瑞典团队
Come on, Barry, there's a Swedish team
准备在我们之前做实验呢
trying to run our experiment before us.
能分点给我们吗?
Can't you spare any?
说心里话 如果情况刚好相反
Be honest, if the shoe was on the other foot,
你会借我液氦吗?
would you do this for me?
- 当然  - 没门
- Yes.  - No chance.
你干什么呢?
What are you doing?
他说讲心里话 我就如实说了
He said be honest, so I was honest.
你妈妈没教过你吗? 这是最好的方案
Didn't your mother tell you? It's the best policy.
所以你怎么想?
So, what do you say?
当然不借
Hell no.
他应该做些铺垫的
He could've softened the blow.
* 宇宙一度又烫又稠密 *
* Our whole universe was in a hot, dense state *
* 140亿年前终于爆了炸... 等着瞧! *
* Then nearly 14 billion years ago expansion started... Wait! *
* 地球开始降温 *
* The Earth began to cool *
* 自养生物来起哄 穴居人发明工具 *
* The autotrophs began to drool, Neanderthals developed tools *
* 我们建长城 我们建金字塔 *
* We built the Wall * * We built the pyramids *
* 数学 自然科学 历史 揭开神秘 *
* Math, Science, History, unraveling the mystery *
* 一切由大爆炸开始 *
* That all started with a big bang *
生活大爆炸 第九季第5集
--==圣城家园SCG字幕组 http://hdscg.com/==--
仅供翻译交流使用, 禁止用于商业用途
协调: 凤梨酥   校对: 红咖喱影
翻译: 毛毛赶作业 夏至未寒 凤梨酥 猫呗打老师
你们干嘛去找Kripke借?
Why do you need Kripke?
为什么不去派对城买氦气?
Why don't you just go to Party City for helium?
派对城: 出售各种派对用品的商店
那我们得跑遍整个加州所有的派对城
We'd have to go to every Party City in California.
五月五日节: 墨西哥的地区性节日
听起来像是五月五日节的你啊
Sounds like you on Cinco de Mayo.
嘿 人们五月七号还在谈论
Hey, people were still talking about that party
那个派对呢
on siete de Mayo.
Leonard 如果个瑞典团队打败了我们
Leonard, if that Swedish team beats us,
我就永远不会喜欢
I will never be able to enjoy
任何他们国家出产的东西了
anything from their country again.
真是可惜 因为瑞典的肉丸
Which is a shame, because Swedish meatballs
是我最喜欢的牙签肉丸
are my favorite toothpick-delivered meatball.
如果你们真的很需要液氦的话 我认识一个人
If you need liquid helium so bad, I know a guy
只要你不问太多问题 他会给你们弄一些的
who can get you some, if you don't ask too many questions.
- 他是谁?  - 他在什么地方工作?
- Who is he?  - Where does he work?
他怎么能弄到氦气?
How does he get the helium?
多少问题才算多?
How many questions are too many questions?
他大概不会给你了
Maybe he's not for you.
四个问题 四个问题才算多
Four questions. There answer's four.
嘿 你知道那天晚上
Hey, you know who went out
谁出去约会了吗? 是Stuart
on a date the other night? Stuart.
哦 不错啊
Oh, good for him.
我也这么想
I thought so, too.
她是个无家可归的人 还是准备作伪证陷害Stuart?
So is she, like, homeless, or framing him for a crime?
他在手机上用一个什么约会软件
He's using some kind of dating app on his phone.
哪一个?
Oh, which one?
大概我们可以让Amy试试
Maybe we can get Amy to try it.
我不知道
I don't know.
Stuart 你能来一下吗?
Stuart, can you come in here?
他给我解释过这个
He tried to explain it to me.
它会显示你周围人的照片
It shows you pictures of people nearby,
你可以划来划去 看起来像个游戏
you swipe them around, it looks kind of like a game.
哦 那如果你输了的话 就要和Stuart约会吧
Oh, and if you lose the game, you have to go out with Stuart.
什么事?
What's up?
你能给我们看看那个约会软件吗?
Can you show us that dating app?
哦 当然
Oh, yeah, sure.
这软件简直改变了我的人生
This thing has changed my life.
哇 你已经约过多少女孩了?
Wow. So how many girls have you met?
两个
Two.
我不用解释
I probably don't need to mention
2和0之间还有一个整数吧
there's an entire number between that and zero.
那它是怎么约女孩的?
Well, so how does it work?
嗯 它会显示
Uh, well, it-it shows me all
我方圆五英里内所有正在使用
the single women in a five-mile radius
这款软件的单身女性
who are using the app.
如果我喜欢她们 我就会点"顶"
If I like the way they look, I hit "thumbs up."
如果不喜欢 就点"踩"
If I don't, "thumbs down."
哦 那什么情况下你会"踩"一个女孩?
Oh, what would make you give a girl a thumbs down?
等我第一次点的时候 我会告诉你的
First time it happens I will let you know.
嘿 那个卖液氦的人回复我了
Oh, hey. I just heard back from the liquid helium guy.
他说什么?
What's he say?
他有我们想要的东西 想今晚见我们
He's got what we need and can meet us tonight.
要这样吗?
Oh, really?
你知道我不喜欢晚上买东西
You know I don't like buying things at night.
2009年一月七号
January 7, 2009.
晚上11点半我去Ralph那里取我的
I went to the Ralph's at 11:30pm to pick up
早餐脆皮麦片 我看到了什么?
Cracklin' Oat Bran for the morning and what did I see?
一个男人正在给麦片货架上货
The man restocking the cereal shelves.
没错 他做了什么?
That's right. And what did he do?
他直接给了你一盒 还叫你瘦竹竿
He handed you the box directly and called you Stretch.
简直就像刚发生一样
It's like it was yesterday.
你到底想不想要液氮?
Do you want liquid helium or not?
我当然想要
Of course I do.
我不想让瑞典小组抢先
I don't want that Swedish team scooping us.
那我就跟他说同意见面了
Then I'm going to tell him we're in.
等下 Leonard 这很不道德
Leonard, wait. This is highly unethical.
我们只是稍微改变了一下规则
We're just bending the rules a little.
我们有很多资金做实验
We have grant money to do the experiment,
我们就把钱花在我们需要的液氮上
so we're going to spend it on the helium we need.
这个和Goldfarb博士不一样
It's not like when Dr. Goldfarb
他声称自己买了电子显微镜
claimed he bought an electron microscope
实际上只是拿钱去和
and he was really just keeping
俄罗斯女孩在Van Nuys同居
a Russian girl in an apartment in Van Nuys.
她在帮他做实验吗?
Was she helping him with his research?
是
Sure.
所以我们到底见不见?
So, are we doing this?
好吧 但他是哪里弄到液氮的?
Okay, but where does he get the helium?
记得吗? 别问太多问题
Remember? Don't ask too many questions?
呃 但这违反了学校的规定
Uh, but this is violating university code.
一点点 但是...
A little, but...
但是爱因斯坦说过
if I may quote Einstein,
"对科学的追求让我们
"The pursuit of science calls us
忽视一切人为的规则"
to ignore the rules set by man"
对哦
Huh.
好吧 干吧
All right, do it.
跟他说我们交易
Tell him we're in.
成了
Done.
网上找不到这话
I can't find that quote on the Internet.
是你自己编的吧?
Did you make that up?
在我回答之前
Before I answer,
我想说你现在的皮肤真是棒呆了
may I just say your skin has never looked better.
你嘴可真甜
Aren't you just made of sugar.
我觉得这很诡异
I'm not sure how I feel about this.
没事的 就是让他给你的手机装个软件而已
Oh, come on, just let him put the app on your phone.
是啊 Stuart用它约了两次会了
Yeah, Stuart got two dates with it.
其中一个本来可以滚床单的 她没说不行
One of which would've ended in sex had she not said no.
好了 装好了
Okay, all set.
好 让我看看
Okay, let me see.
这个不行 不行
Nope, nope,
也不行...
nope...
这个很棒!
Oh, he's cute!
这个泪珠一样的纹身
Doesn't a teardrop tattoo
是不是代表他谋杀过什么人?
mean he murdered someone?
他还为此很难过
And he's sad about it.
- 嗨  - 大家好
- Hey.  - Hello.
- 嘿  - 嘿 我以为你们会玩到很晚呢
- Hey.  - Hey, I thought you were gonna be out late?
你要是想让我晚回来
If you wanted me to stay out later,
你应该多给一些零用钱
you should've given me more spending money.
你们在干什么啊?
What are you guys up to?
我们给Amy装了一个约会软件
We put Amy on a dating app,
我们正在看里面都有什么
and we're seeing what's out there.
有趣! 让我也看看
Oh, fun! Let me see.
呃 这个不行...
Uh, no...
不行 这个肯定不行
no, uh, definitely not.
这人怎么了?
What was wrong with that guy?
呃 他是印度人
Uh, he's Indian.
我们已经有一个印度人了
We've already got one of those.
哦 我们应该找一个拉美人
Ooh, we should find a nice Latino.
我们正缺这个品种
It really round us out.
嘿 我也要试一试
Hey, I want to try.
呃 打扰一下... 我能把手机拿回来吗?
Uh, excuse me, c... can I have my phone back?
等一会 我正在帮你找
Hang on, I'm trying to find you
你的下一任真爱呢
the next great love of your life.
这人会成为你孩子的父亲
The man who will father your children.
快看 这个编着小辫子的白人怎么样?
Okay, yes or no on white guy with dreadlocks?
那应该就是他了
That must be him.
当然
Oh, of course.
一辆没有任何特点的白面包车
An nondescript, white panel van.
你应该对这句话很熟吧:
You may be familiar with it from the sentence:
"他们的尸体在一辆没有任何特点的白面包车里被发现"
"Their bodies were found in a nondescript, white panel van"
嘿
Hey.
怎么了?
What's up?
我是Leonard
Uh, I'm Leonard.
- 这是我朋友...  - 我是Skippy
- This is my friend...  - I'm Skippy.
全名Skippy Cavanaugh
Skippy Cavanaugh.
好吧
Great.
你们带现金了吗?
You got the cash?
呃 带了 在这儿
Uh, yeah, uh, right here.
等一下 等等
Wait, hold on, hold on.
我们怎知道你会不会
How do we know that you're not gonna
拿了钱就马上跑路?
take the money and drive away?
Skippy 你干嘛?
What ya doing, Skippy?
这是70年代的罪案剧教我们的
Exactly what 1970s television crime dramas have taught us.
你先把液氮交出来
You give us the helium first.
呃 我怎么知道你们不会
Oh, how do I know you're not gonna
拿上液氮就跑了?
drive away without paying me?
我想我不是唯一一个
Guess I'm not the only one
看过70年代罪案剧的人
who watches '70s television crime dramas.
听着 你可以相信我们
Look, you can trust us.
我们都是有名的科学家
We're respected scientists.
呃 他是科学家
Well, he is.
我是个找不到真爱的
I'm a wedding planner,
婚礼策划师
who can't find love himself.
这是讽刺 但重点是
It's ironic, but the point is
我们不能信任你
we can't trust you.
你是车库里一个毫无特点的人
You're a sketchy character in a parking garage.
呃 好吧 在我看来
Yeah, well, from my perspective,
这也是你们给我的印象
that's how you two appear to me.
好吧 我从没想过会这样子
Well, I never thought of it like that.
小子 参照系会慢慢移到你那边的 是吧?
Boy, frame of reference will just sneak up on you, won't it?
我朋友对付钱是很有诚意的
My friend does make a decent point about the money.
我觉得直接把钱交给你不合适
I don't feel comfortable just handing it over up front.
呃... 没钱 没液氮
Ah..ah...ah, no money, no helium.
看来我们陷入僵局了
Seems we're at a, uh, stalemate.
这么说不准确
Not technically.
在国际象棋里 僵局是指任何一个子
In chess, a stalemate refers to a situation
都已经没有步可以走了
in which there are no remaining moves.
呃 你还有很多步可以走
Uh, you have plenty of moves available.
你可以放倒我们再把钱偷走
You could beat us up and steal the money.
也可以杀了我们 你懂的
You could kill us, you know.
说真的 唯一限制你行动的就是你的想象力
Really, you're only limited by your imagination.
呃
Huh.
这么些年 我说"僵局"的时候
All these years, I've been using "stalemate",
我仅仅是指"僵局"而已
when I really mean “impasse”.
我好像犯蠢了
I feel foolish.
我觉得不管这是无路可走
I don't think it matters if this is a stalemate
还是个僵局 还是什么墨西哥对峙
or an impasse or a Mexican standoff.
我们到底怎么交易?
What are we gonna do here?
等等 等等 这怎么能是墨西哥对峙?
Oh, whoa, whoa, how can it be a Mexican standoff?
大家都知道 墨西哥对峙至少需要三方的参与
Everybody knows you need three sides for that.
不一定啊
Not necessarily.
很多人说 墨西哥对峙的重点在于
Uh, many argue the essence of a Mexican standoff
没有人能够不受到任何伤害
is that no one can walk away from the conflict
而走出当前的处境
without incurring harm.
我没明白
Hmm, I don't follow.
举个例子来说
Let me give you an example.
今天早些时候
Earlier today,
我分析了你发来的邮件的页眉
I decoded the headers on your e-mail,
发现你叫Kenneth Fitzgerald
and I know that your name is Kenneth Fitzgerald.
通过你的名字 我进一步找到了你的住址和工作单位
From that, I figured out where you live and where you work.
那么 如果要构成一个墨西哥对峙的局面
Now, to make this a Mexican standoff,
我就会说 比如 呃
I would say something like, uh,
"你要是不把液氦给我们 我们就报警"
"You give us the helium or I'll turn you in to the authorities"
这是在威胁我?
Is that a threat?
对啊 没错 你懂了吧
Yeah, exactly. See, you're getting it.
好吧 知道吗? 我也知道你们在哪工作
Yeah, well, I know where you work, all right?
要是你们敢找我的麻烦 我也会把你们的事抖出来
And if you mess with me, I'll report you,
然后再狠狠揍你们一顿
then I'll pound your asses into the ground.
这就对了! 现在我们的处境就属于墨西哥对峙
Perfect! Now we really are in a Mexican standoff.
这是不是就是那种
Is this one of those times
捡了芝麻 丢了西瓜的情况?
where I've won the battle but lost the war?
好像是吧 Skippy
Afraid so, Skippy.
我就跟你说我们不应该晚上出来买东西
I told you we shouldn't go shopping at night.
好了 好了 大家都冷静点
All right, let's all just calm down.
没人想报警
Nobody wants to report anybody.
不 我不喜欢这种感觉 我不干了
No, I don't like this. I'm out.
别 别 别 等一下 先别走
No, no, no. Wait, don't go.
你让我解释一下
Just let me explain.
我们是物理学家 我们已经花了一年的时间
We're physicists, and we're trying to prove
想要证明我们提出的一个假设
a hypothesis that we've been working on for over a year.
是吗? 什么假设?
Really? What's the hypothesis?
时间和空间可以被解释为
Space-time can be interpreted as
多面超流体的一个表面
the surface of an n-dimensional superfluid.
嗯 有可能 有可能
Hmm. Could be, could be.
所以呢
Go on.
现在有一个瑞典的科研团队 他们读了我们的论文
Okay, but now there's this Swedish team that read our paper
就想抢在我们前面发表实验成果
and they're trying to beat us to our own discovery.
我们真的很需要这些液氦
We really need this helium.
我也很抱歉 我骗你说
And I'm sorry I lied about
我是找不到真爱的婚礼策划师
being a wedding planner who can't find love.
不过我现在真的单身 万一你有认识的合适的女孩...
Although I am currently single, if you know anybody.
钱给你 现在可以了吗?
Here's the money. Can we do this?
好吧
Okay.
真为那些窃取你们研究成果的科学家感到丢人
It's a shame about those scientists ripping you off.
我还以为瑞典的小伙伴们
I expected a higher ethical standard
道德水准挺高的呢
from our friends in Sweden.
其实在我们这个领域这种事情挺常见的
It's actually pretty common in our field.
但也没什么办法
Not much you can do about it.
其实 只要有足够的钱
Well, for the right amount of money,
并且知道他们住在那里
if you know where they live,
那还是有挺多办法对付他们的
there's, uh, plenty we could do about it.
你听见了吗 Leonard?
Did you hear that, Leonard?
我们有挺多办法的
There's plenty we could do about it.
你有名片吗?
Do you have a card?
好了 连好了
Okay, here we go.
这样大家都能看到了
Now everyone can see.
好了
All right.
你们觉得这个有点内斜视的Mike怎么样?
Where do we stand on cross-eyed Mike?
这样他就没法看别的女孩了
You know he won't be looking at other girls.
除非她们坐在他的鼻子上
Unless they're sitting on the end of his nose.
好了好了 不喜欢
Okay, okay, okay. Thumbs down.
下一位
Next.
哦 看他的牙那么小
Ew, check out his tiny teeth.
他看起来就像只海豚
He looks like a man-dolphin.
那要是他活儿好的话 Amy可以奖励他一条鱼
Wait, if he's good in bed, she can throw him a fish.
我爱你 Amy
I love you, Amy.
你们差不多就算了吧 我感觉有点自责
Okay, I'm starting to feel guilty.
我们这样是不是不太好啊?
Aren't we being a little mean?
说得对
That's a fair point.
当着别人的面 我们肯定不会这么取笑他们
We wouldn't make fun of someone like this to their face.
看啊 是Stuart!
Look, it's Stuart!
你可以选择不要待在这间屋子里了
You may want to leave the room.
往这边走 Harvey叔叔
Right this way, Uncle Harvey.
你能别这么干了吗?
Will you stop with that already?
我不想太引人注意
I'm trying not to attract attention.
向清洁女工脱帽致意不会引人注意吗?
And tipping his hat to the cleaning lady didn't do that?
她说了西班牙语的"晚上好" Harvey叔叔还能怎么样?
She said, "Buenas noches." What was he supposed to do?
赶紧做实验吧
Let's just start the experiment.
Leonard 我们得先编好供词
Leonard, we should probably have our story straight
万一被抓了也好有个对策
in case we get caught.
我们不会被抓的
We're not getting caught.
谁也说不准嘛
Well, you can't be sure of that.
万一那个卖液氦的人出卖了我们呢?
What if the helium dealer rats us out?
万一Kripke问我们液氦的来源呢?
What if Kripke asks where we got it?
万一学校去检查我的家谱
What if the university checks my family tree
发现我没有一个叔叔叫Harvey呢?
and finds out I don't have an Uncle Harvey?
卖液氦的人才懒得管我们 Kripke没有权利管我们
The dealer doesn't care, Kripke has no authority over us,
而你和一个金属罐子的亲属关系
and you being related to a metal container
就可以解释Harvey叔叔的事了
would explain a lot.
帮我把这个连上
Help me hook this up.
- 啊哦  - 怎么了?
- Uh-oh.  - What?
- 你看到这个标签了吗?  - 写了什么?
- Well, did you see this sticker?  - What is it?
已经被撕掉了一部分 不过剩下的部分写着
It's partially torn off, but the segment that remains reads:
"归属权为" 还有字母"U"
"Property of" and the letter "U."
有可能代表南加州大学或者加州大学洛杉矶分校
It's probably USC or UCLA.
是啊 不过万一是"归属权为美国政府所有"呢?
Yeah, but what if it's "Property of U.S. Government"?
在德克萨斯州的Amarillo有一个国家氦元素储备地
There's a national helium reserve in Amarillo, Texas.
如果这罐液氦是从那里偷出来的
If this was stolen from there,
我们就触犯了联邦的法律
we're accessories to a federal crime.
先别急着下结论
Let's not jump to conclusions.
很多机构都是"U"开头的
A lot of things start with "U."
说得也对
That's true.
美国空军 美国国防部
There's the U.S. Air Force,
美国海军 都是字母"U"开头的
U.S. Department of Defense, U.S. Navy,
对于你我来说 说不定监狱也是
"you" and I are going to jail.
听着 我们可以继续按计划做实验
Listen, we can do the experiment as planned
要不我们先下手为强打败瑞典队
and beat the Swedish team to the punch,
要不就和我们的梦想吻别
or we can kiss our dreams good-bye because we were
因为我们胆子太小不敢违法
to afraid to break a few rules.
女士您好
Ma'am.
好了 大家都记住规则了吧?
Okay, does everyone remember the rules?
如果这人裸上身 喝一小口
If he's shirtless, one sip.
和宠物合照 喝两小口
Posing with a pet, two sips.
裸上身和宠物合照 就大口喝
Pet and shirtless, chug like it's your job.
下一个!
And pull!
我有一条一样的内裤!
I have that same underwear!
大口喝!
Chug!
Amy 你收到一条消息
Mm, Amy, you're getting a text.
嗯 把手机给我
Oh, um, give me that.
"昨晚过得很开心"
"I had a great time last night"
不 不 别... 别读了
No, no, st... stop reading that.
- Dave是谁?  - 我...
- Who's Dave?  - I...
你昨晚出去约会了吗?
You went on a date last night?
你在和谁谈恋爱吗?
Are you seeing someone?
不 不是... 你说的那样
No, it... it's not like that.
"我想再和你约会一次"?
"And I'd love to take you out again"?
- Amy!  - 咋回事?
- Amy!   - What?
- 难以置信  - 天啊
- Can't believe it.  - Oh, my God.
好吧 就是你说的那样
Okay, it's like that.
多谢你能回来
Thank you for coming back.
我通常都不会这样的
Yeah, well, normally I wouldn't,
但是我女儿带同学回家过夜了
but my daughter's having a sleepover, and there's only
家里的高音咆哮只有水果姐才能盖得住
so much screaming and Katy Perry a man can take.
如果你能把我们的钱还回来
Anyway, if you could just give us our money back,
你可以把你的液氦带走 我们也走了
you can have your helium and we'll be on our way.
好的 出了什么问题了吗?
Yeah, well, is there something wrong with it?
没有 我们改主意了
No, nothing. We just changed our mind.
他是四眼仔 我又是百科全书
He has glasses and I'm a know-it-all;
我们不是进监狱的料
we are not built for prison.
好吧 我明白了
Yeah, I hear you.
你们都是好人 所以...
Well, you're good guys, so I'll, uh...
我会把液氦拿回去的
I'll take the helium off your hands.
谢谢你
Thank you.
但是你们的钱就拿不回去了
But you ain't getting your money back.
你居然利用我们?
You're taking advantage of us?
我们都商量好署名问题了
We clarified nomenclature together.
听着 我和下一个人一样
Look, I enjoy semantic digressions
都喜欢文字游戏 但生意就是生意
as much as the next guy, but, uh, this is business.
好的好的
You know what?
没事的 你可以把钱留着
It's fine. Keep the money.
我们只想把这事翻篇
We just want to be done with this.
没问题 但是我还要收
No problem, but I am gonna have to charge you
一点液氦重装运费
a small helium restocking fee.
我不理解
I don't understand.
他还想要钱
He wants more money.
好吧 最好别多于一千美金
Well, it better not be more than a thousand dollars,
我就带了那么多
that's all I've got on me.
正巧就是这么多
That's exactly how much it is.
终于
Finally,
有人比咱们还神机妙算了
something breaks our way.
不敢相信 你居然在和人约会
I can't believe you're seeing someone
而且我们毫不知情
and we don't even know about it.
对啊 你为什么不告诉我们?
Yeah, why wouldn't you tell us?
因为这事又陌生又奇怪
Because it's new and weird
我想自己先弄明白
and I'm just trying to figure it all out.
而且我知道
And I knew
假如我告诉了你们
if I told you guys I had been out
我和几个人出去约会过 你们就会激动得要死
with a few people that you'd get way too excited about it.
几个人?
A few people?
- 你说啥?! Amy!  - Amy!
- What?! Amy!  - Amy!
那么 允许我们问问情况如何吗?
So, are we allowed to ask how it's going?
还可以
It's going fine.
基本都是相约去喝喝咖啡
It's mostly just been meeting people for coffee.
啥... ?!
Wha...?!
我以为大家会...
I thought we were all...
别在意
Never mind.
我... 我以为你没准备好
I... I thought you weren't ready
开始和人约会呢
to start seeing people.
我没有什么约会的经验
Well, I don't have much experience dating,
所以我觉得可能出去约会几次
so I decided it would be good for me
会对我有益
to, you know, get out there a little.
这样挺好的
Well, good for you.
谢谢你
Thank you.
那你和几个人约会过了呢?
And how many guys have you gone out with?
但愿少于两个
Please be less than two.
- 三个  - 该死
- Three.  - Damn it.
好吧 瑞典人要打败我们了
Well, the Swedes might beat us,
但是至少咱们不会在监狱里被拉帮结派
but at least we won't get gang-noogied in prison.
你是不是除了"监狱宝贝蛋"没看过别的监狱电影?
Is Ernest Goes to Jail the only prison movie you've seen?
Scared Straight: 恐怖监狱 1978年上映电影
"恐怖监狱"把我吓直了 Leonard
It scared me straight, Leonard.
嘿 我一直在想
Hey, I've been thinking.
是我太小气了
I was being petty.
你们可以用我的液氦
You can have my helium.
谢谢你 Barry
Thank you, Barry.
但是你们要把我的名字加到论文里
But you have to add my name to your paper.
太荒谬了
That's preposterous.
我不知道 挺公平的
I don't know, seems fair.
你们也可以不带我继续研究
You can't do it without me.
可以让我们商量一下吗?
Can you give us a minute?
慢慢谈
Take your time.
为了戏剧效果 我会倒退出门外
I'll walk out backwards for dramatic effect.
我不想被这样敲竹杠
I don't like being extorted like this.
尤其不想被他敲
Especially by him of all people.
我也不想 但是我们还有什么选择呢?
Me neither, but what other choice do we have?
我保证这是最后一次了
I promise this is the last time.
维基百科上这么说
It says right here on Wikipedia.
"墨西哥对峙是指至少
"A Mexican standoff is a confrontation between
三个政党两两间的对峙"
at least three parties."
你怎么能相信维基百科
How can you trust Wikipedia
他们明明说了三个政党 却说只有"两两"?
if they use "between" to refer to three parties?
他们应该说"三个" 对吧?
They should've used "among," right?
如果想要高大上一点 可以说"三者"
Or "amongst",  if they were feeling whimsically archaic.
好了 闲言少叙
All right, enough with the chitchat.
我们还看不看"监狱宝贝蛋"了?
Are we gonna watch Ernest Goes to Jail or not?
当然要看
Absolutely.
但是别被吓到 这个电影
But don't be surprised if this movie sets you
- 会让你以后都循规蹈矩的  - 我乐于改变
- on the straight and narrow.  - I am open to change.